So, I just want to talk about for a
moment for all of you who are going
through a season of your life that looks
like "What are you doing?" Keep walking.
Keep walking.
Because the what ifs that you have about
your marriage, the what ifs that you
have about your health, the what ifs
that you have about your children, the
what ifs that you have about your
career, the what ifs that you have about
your emotions, the what ifs that that
you have will only be answered when you
walk.
So, keep walking. That's all the
disciples did. They walked with him. The
disciples are walking. Everybody say,
"The disciples are walking."
And the disciples are walking with a
Jesus that they do not fully understand,
even though they have been radically
changed. Even though they have been
wonderfully exposed, the the disciples
are living in it, and there is a
difference between living in it and
looking at it. Now, you're like, "You
already said that." I'm going to say it
again, because it is so easy for you to
look at somebody else's life and envy
them and be jealous of them, but you
might be jealous of a life that you're
only seeing the front side of. And if
you ever saw the back side of their
life, you might not be bitter about
yours, because there is a chance that
the cost that they are paying to be who
they are is greater than the toll that
you would want to pay. So, don't be
jealous. And also,
don't judge.
Don't judge.
BECAUSE WE ARE ALL
WALKING. WE ARE LIKE the disciples.
There are things that we don't
understand, and we will not until after.
I heard about a poem that Corrie ten
Boom used to love.
I thought that she wrote it,
but I found out that she was quoting it
from Grant Colfax Tullar,
who was a poet.
And I want you to listen to this,
because
she read it as a Holocaust survivor.
She read it after forgiving people who
tortured her family.
She read it after surviving something
that most of us would have stumbled
over.
And she read this poem
called The Weaver.
My life is but a weaving between my God
and me.
I cannot choose the colors he weaveth
steadily.
Oft times he weaveth sorrow,
and I, in foolish pride,
forget
he sees the upper
and I the underside.
The underside.
Not till the loom is silent
and the shuttles cease to fly, will God
unroll the canvas and reveal the reason
why.
The dark threads are as needful
in the weaver's skillful hand as the
threads of gold and silver
in the pattern he has planned.
What she's saying is, I don't see the
picture from my perspective.
I don't see what his hands are doing
while I am going through the hardships
of my life.
And it is the weaver that I worship.
And I walk with him and I talk with him,
but I often wonder,
"What are you doing?"
I can tell I might need to break this
down a little bit. So, let me show you
something.
Holly and I have a a a great marriage.
Great marriage.
Yeah, I picked the right partner and I'm
reaping the benefits ever since.
Praise the Lord.
For our uh 20th anniversary a while
back, Shell made us
um this
this cross stitch.
Can you see it?
Kind of.
Right?
Like you can kind of tell what it is.
It kind of looks like she didn't do a
good job.
It kind of looks like she needs to go
back to cross stitch class,
take a couple remedial weeks, but of
course,
if you see the other side,
you can see she did pretty good.
You can see she made me look just like I
did on that
fateful day with no beard, standing
before my wife in my S&K suit about
three sizes too big for me.
And there we are
like this
on this side, but
every marriage does have an underside.
And I just want you to remember when you
look at everybody's Easter pictures on
Instagram in about a week,
they're showing this,
but they probably went through this in
the car before they got to Sears to take
the picture. That's a callback reference
from the '80s.
>> [applause]
>> You see what I'm saying? It This is uh
Zoom back in, y'all. What are you doing?
This is
This is what it looks like,
and this is how it's lived.
I said, "This is what it looks like,
and this is how
it's lived." She She got out the car the
other day, and she asked me, "Does my
hair look good messy or bad messy?" Now,
after 20-something years,
I can tell you that the answer to that
automatically is good messy, but I can
also tell you there is a difference
between good messy
and bad messy.
And and good messy is when you are
trusting God in your life to work out
the details that you can't control, and
you are trusting God's sovereignty in
your life for situations that are too
big for you. Good messy is in a marriage
where we fight for the marriage, where
we fight with each other instead of
against each other, and we fight for
each other. Cuz every marriage has an
underside. Every marriage that looks
like this looks like this somewhere.
Every marriage that looks like this,
where the couple has their debts paid
off, had conversations about, "Are you
really bringing that coffee table into
my house? And did it really cost?" I
remember the first time she told me she
wanted to spend $400 on a coffee table.
I said, "You better find one that has
some dings and dents in it. You better
find one that's busted out the top of
it. $400 for a coffee table?" See,
because we are still weaving together
our values for money. She has a value
for a coffee table. I didn't even drink
coffee at the time. How am I supposed to
pay $400 for something I don't even
drink? I'm not even going to use. It
looks like this. Every marriage, in
terms of sexual relationships, in terms
of communication, in terms of conflict
management, [clears throat]
it always looks like this. So, what I'm
trying to say is, don't confuse what it
looks like with how it's lived, or you
might give up on something great because
of something gross, and you might live
give up on something miraculous because
of something messy. And when God is
bringing something together in your
life, remember you have to trust him
with the underside.
>> [applause]
>> That might be the whole word for
somebody today.
Trust him with the underside. I know
it's ugly, but trust him. I know it's
crazy, but trust him. I know it's
confusing, but trust him. I know it's
not coming together as fast as you want
it, but trust him. I know you can't
FIGURE OUT WHAT IT IS YET, but trust
him. I know everybody around you is
acting kind of judgmental, BUT DON'T
JUDGE THE UNDERSIDE, because in GOD'S
HAND, THE DARK threads are just as
important as the light threads. And all
things work together for the good of
them who are called according to his
purpose. So, if he called me according
to his purpose, that means there will be
an underside that he oversees, AND I
CANNOT JUDGE WHAT HE'S MAKING BY the
moment that I'm in, or I will be like
the disciples that saw the cross as a
failure. But this was NOT THE FAILURE,
THIS WAS THE FOUNDATION. And isn't it
amazing that the disciples walked with
Jesus into the most confusing moments of
their life, but the most confusing
moment was the one that he used the
most. I can tell you, looking back on 46
years of living, that some of the times
that I was most confused were some of
the times that he most used. So, don't
give up on God just because you're on
the underside. It might be ugly on the
underside. It might be uncomfortable on
the other side. It may be inconvenient
on the underside. It may be
embarrassing. It may be humiliating. You
might have to ask some questions. You
may not understand until after.
When Jesus
was glorified,
they got it, and then they went, "Oh!
Is this?"
And the faith
is to
The faith
is to make it
through the lows,
so you can get
TO THE OH.
OH.
And and meanwhile, the disciples
are walking,
and the crowds, that's number two,
are waving.
And they are waving palm branches.
And these palm branches are not random.
I remember a few years ago in church,
actually, it must have been about 15
years ago, because it was back when I
used to copy everything my buddy Perry
Noble did in church, cuz I know what I
was doing. And he had people break these
glow sticks one Sunday, and on Palm
Sunday, they all raised them in the air,
and they were singing uh shine your
light and let the whole world see for
the glory of the risen king and
everybody broke the glow stick and
raised it up in the air on Palm Sunday
and we were using it to represent all
the people we wanted to see come to
Christ and we were raising the glow
sticks and I read this young girl on
Twitter. She said, "My mom asked me, did
we have palm branches in church on Palm
Sunday?" And I had to tell her, "No,
they had glow sticks." And I was like,
that's just Elevation, right? Like not a
lot of tradition around here. In fact,
this is the first time I've preached on
the donkey on Palm Sunday uh in in about
10 to 15 years.
But but before I can even talk about the
donkey,
I got to talk about the crowds.
Because we named
this Sunday
after what the crowds held in their hand
and what they waved as a sign of
victory.
The palm branch represented victory.
Like when a great conquering king would
take
a new territory and come back into town
on a war horse, they would wave these
palm branches and these myrtles and THEY
WOULD SHOUT, "HOSANNA!
BLESSED IS HE WHO COMES IN THE NAME OF
THE LORD." AND THEY DO IT THREE TIMES.
"HOSANNA! [screaming]
BLESSED is he." Cuz the victor was
coming back and they would wave the
BRANCHES TALKING ABOUT, "HOSANNA!
Blessed is he." And this is a scripture
that they were quoting from Psalm 118
verse 26.
"Hosanna! [screaming]
Blessed is he who comes in the name of
the Lord." Now, Jesus is headed to a
cross and he's coming through Jerusalem
and about 120,000 people are gathered to
celebrate the Passover festival and it's
crowded in the streets of Jerusalem and
they're shouting out, "Save now." That's
what Hosanna means. "Save now." Cuz
don't we want God to get it out of us
and get us out of it right now? And
don't we want God to do what he's going
to do right now? And since they they
just got word that Lazarus was in the
ground but he got up, maybe they figured
that this prophet, this this priest,
this Messiah, whatever he was, could do
for them what they had waited for the
king to do and so this they are shouting
Hosanna, blessed is he who comes in the
name of the Lord and they're shouting
loud. I believe that as they are
shouting Hosanna, which is a praise
word, Jesus can already hear the echoes
of crucify him, which the same crowds
would be shouting on Friday.
Don't ever get too attached to people's
praise.
>> [applause]
>> Cuz if you live by it, you'll die when
they take it away.
Even don't be too attached to when your
kids think you're a good parent.
Sometimes you might have to take their
phone and they might call you the devil.
Now, what you going to do about it?
You're running a popularity contest or a
household? Don't be too attached to
people's praise.
Don't even be too attached to your
parents' praise. Sometimes your parents
see you as their product and they can't
even guide you as good as God can
because they're trying to get you to
fulfill something that they didn't
accomplish in their life and only God
can show you what your next step is. So,
don't be too attached to their praise.
If you live when they give it, you'll
die when they take it away. Don't be too
attached to people's praise. Don't be
too attached to the likes. Don't be too
attached to the encouragement of your
boss. What you going to do if your boss
moves divisions? What you going to do if
you get a boss that doesn't like you?
You still going to work hard because
you're God's child. Jesus never moved by
the approval of people. Jesus never
moved for the yays of the crowds. Jesus
never moved for the high fives even of
his own disciples. Jesus was not moved
by the crowd. He moved through the
crowd. I'm going somewhere. The
disciples are walking. The crowds are
waving and they are shouting Hosanna.
But they will not still be shouting when
he is led like a lamb to the slaughter.
They will not still be shouting when
Pilate puts him up, turns him over and
hangs him to die. They will not still be
shouting on Saturday when his body lays
in a tomb. What are you trying to say?
Don't confuse loud with loyal.
Don't confuse loud with loyal. The
crowds are waving. The crowds will wave,
that's fine. But Jesus was not moved by
the crowds.
And I don't know who this point is for
because
it's it's really just an incidental
point to get me to the main point of
this message.
Cuz while the crowds are waving,
the donkey
Can we talk about the donkey?
I know we're all impressed by Palm
Sunday.
But why can't we call it Donkey Sunday?
Because it doesn't have the same ring to
it?
Because while the disciples are walking
and the crowds are waving, watch what
the donkey is doing. The donkey is
waiting.
So, now the crowds are walking.
Calm down, Fred. Give it to him slow.
The crowds are waving. "Hosanna!
Hosanna!" And the donkey is waiting.
Now, this is really fun. Go back to John
chapter 11 verse 4.
You know, John doesn't give a lot of
details about the donkey. In fact,
when he talks about the donkey, he says
something so simple, you almost just
read right over it. It said, "Jesus
found a young donkey and sat on it."
AND THAT'S ALL THE DETAILS WE GET FROM
JOHN.
JOHN, LIKE A TRUE MAN,
JUST GIVES you the bottom line. Yeah, he
found a donkey and he sat on it. But you
know what this tells me?
I'm speculating but I have good reason.
I studied.
John
wasn't one of the disciples that got
sent to get the donkey.
That's what it tells me.
It's like my kids fighting around the
table, you know, they'll be trying to
tell a story at dinner and they'll be
like, "Shut up, let me tell it." Or I
mean, sorry, we're at church. We're
pastor's family. "Please be quiet.
Please hearken unto my voice." That's
what they say at my table. What about
your table? They say shut up at your
house? What's wrong with you? You're a
terrible parent.
They say, "SHUT UP, IT'S MY STORY. LET
ME TELL IT."
AND I almost felt when John said, "Jesus
found a young donkey and sat on it." And
then just went right on to Psalm 118:26
and the palm branches and all of the
wonderful things, I almost felt Peter
speak UP AND SAY, "SHUT UP, JOHN.
YOU WEREN'T THERE.
LET ME TELL IT."
SO, in Mark's gospel, flip over to Mark
real quick cuz this is the underside.
This is the the side of the story from
the one who was there. In Mark chapter
11, you get a little fuller account. You
get more than just Jesus found a donkey
and sat on it and rode on into
Jerusalem. You get a little bit clearer
picture and you get a little bit more
detail and I want to read it to you from
Mark chapter 11. As they approached
Jerusalem, same disciples walking toward
Jerusalem, and came to Bethphage and
Bethany at the Mount of Olives, Jesus
sent two of his disciples. We don't know
which two. I'm speculating that it was
Peter based on the nature of the job.
You know, you got some disciples that
you need to pray for you and then you
have some disciples that you need to do
other stuff for you that isn't quite as
spiritual. And watch what Jesus told
them to do verse two. Saying to them,
"Go to the village ahead of you and just
as you enter it, you will find a colt,
that's a baby donkey, tied there which
no one has ever ridden. Untie it and
bring it here.
If anyone asks you, 'Why are you doing
this?' say,
'The Lord needs it and will send it back
here shortly.' Skinner, I can't skip
over this and talk about the donkey
being borrowed because I'm thinking
about the fact that Jesus borrowed two
things around Easter. One was a donkey
and one was a tomb.
But see, it wasn't exactly borrowed the
appropriate way, right? This is not
technically how you should borrow
something, right? And so, that's why I
think that Jesus needed Peter to do
something that was so dumb
that it would take a dumb disciple to do
it.
Do I have any dumb disciples in the room
today
who aren't the smartest,
who aren't exactly the sharpest tools in
the drawer, but Jesus, if you need
something to hit something, I'll hit
something for you. That's Peter. Peter's
kind of dull but he'll do it. Tell your
neighbor, "I'm dull but I'll do it."
That's why I think the Lord called me to
start the church when I was 25, when I
was dumb enough to do stuff. I didn't
know how to run a profit and loss
statement. I didn't know how to check a
ledger. All I knew how TO DO WAS ASK THE
Lord and if the Lord told me to give
everybody glow sticks, I gave them a
glow sticks. I didn't care if Aunt Ethel
liked it or not. I was dumb enough to
break a glow stick and tell them happy
Easter. I was dumb enough to do some
stuff and the problem with some of us is
that we've gotten SMARTER THAN A DONKEY.
BUT WHEN JESUS WAS LOOKING FOR something
to come into town on, HE DID NOT LOOK
FOR A SCHOLAR. HE DID NOT LOOK FOR THE
head of the class. HE DID NOT LOOK FOR A
VALEDICTORIAN TO BE HIS VESSEL. He said,
"I NEED A DONKEY. I WONDER WHO I CAN
TRUST ENOUGH TO TAKE MY word without
detail, TO TAKE MY WORD without
explanation, TO TAKE MY WORD WITHOUT THE
CROSS REFERENCE AND DO WHAT I NEED YOU
TO DO."
HEY, thanks for stopping by my YouTube
channel. I hope you were blessed today.
[music] If you were, share this with
somebody. Like and subscribe and leave
me a comment. Let me know where you're
watching from, [music] what we can pray
for you about. Hope to see you back here
again really soon.